Chris Hamlin 1390 W Crape Rd. Queen Creek, AZ 85140 (480) 444-6979 Silver Valley Elementary 9737 E. Toledo Avenue Mesa, AZ 85212 (480) 474-6920

Professional Goal

I will support and encourage those with whom I work. I will promote a collaborative school culture that uses data to make informed decisions.

"The classroom looks and feels awesome. You have created a wonderful learning environment."

Michael Hallock Retired Principal – Quartz Hill Elementary

Chris is active in taking every opportunity to learn from observations and experiences. He is not afraid to engage in conversations with different stakeholders on campus. Chris seems to be very focused on teaching/learning processes; including assessments and engagement strategies.

Mike De La Torre Practicum Clinical Supervisor

"Words alone are not enough to say how much I've enjoyed working with you. You've been so easy going and kind, especially when I needed tech help..."

Peggy Harrison Retired 3rd Grade Teacher Gilbert Public Schools

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE & ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Queen Creek Unified School District

Grades 4, 6 – Teacher 2018 to Present

Gilbert Public Schools

Innovation Coordinator2017 to 2018Grades 3, 4, 6 – Teacher2005 to 2017

Cabinet Member (2006 - 2010) (2012 - 2014) (2019-2020) **PLC Facilitator** (2012 - 2015)

- Honored and selected by peers to represent school as Teacher of the Year
- Honored by classroom parents and selected by Burch and Cracchiolo as Maricopa county's Teacher of the month
- Created and led the Silver Valley Elementary site council team
- **Presented** at the Behavior Education Technology Conference (BET-C) with experiences in the Makerspace initiative
- **Presented** "Tech Tools for the Elementary Teacher 2.0" at Gilbert's Scholarship Educational Technology Innovation (SETI) event multiple years
- Worked collaboratively with K-6 teachers to align instruction with their current learning targets
- Designed and conducted workshops to train teachers how to use ATI/Galileo to create common formative assessments and improve instruction
- Created administrative multimedia presentations
- Redesigned the school library to account for 21st century learning
- **Held Office** on Multiple Committees:
 - Teacher/Superintendent Dialogue Committee
 - Scholarship Educational Technology Innovation (SETI) Improvement committee
 - Imagination, Innovation and Inspiration Committee
 - Computer Lab Assistant
 - Positive Behavior Intervention Support (PBIS) Committee
 - Arizona State STEM Advocates
- **Created and maintained** a STEM challenge club during lunch for the intermediate grades that averaged 70 students five days per week
- **Initiated** collaboration committees with family members to support the implementation of Common Core mathematical standards

Chris Hamlin Page 2

Campo Verde High School (Grades 9 – 12) Val Vista Lakes Elementary (Grades K – 6) Title I Summer School (Grades 4-6) **DEAN (Intern) - Spring 2016**

DEAN (Intern) – Spring 2017

- Modeled presence by going into every classroom every day and supporting the needs of teachers
- Held office as a peer coach within the structure of clinical supervision to provide formative feedback to teachers
- **Created, analyzed, and presented** a four-year longitudinal study on behavior trends at Campo Verde High School to improve discipline
- Conducted a curricular gap analysis as a data-driven school improvement measure
- **Promoted** the **success** of students by supervising after school operations while showing integrity and acting in an ethical manner

Education and Certifications

Masters of Science in Educational Leadership

Western Governors University Salt Lake City, UT 84107

Bachelors of Arts in Education

Bachelors of Science in Psychology

Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ 85287

Arizona Certified Principal K – 12 Arizona Certified Teacher K – 8

Structure English Immersion (SEI) endorsed Gifted Teaching Endorsement (In Progress)

Professional Reference

Allison Carmichael, Current Principal/Supervisor, (480) 474-6920

Joan Henry, Former Principal/Supervisor, (480) 327-9938

Joe Roselle, Director, Grants and Partnerships (480) 205-3590

Mike De La Torre, Principal (480) 262-9041

Peggy Harrison, Retired Teacher, (480) 221-1348